# **Zachary Whiting**

A full-stack web developer, in the process of being certified by the University of Utah Online Coding Bootcamp, having experience with all stages of web development and a proven ability to adapt to and quickly learn new programming languages and APIs.

### **PROJECTS**

**Media 4U** — <u>Repository</u> | <u>Application</u> — Interactive web application used to search for movies and books from The Movie Database and the Google Books APIs and to store them in client side storage.

**Photo Port** — <u>Repository</u> | <u>Application</u> — Single-page React Application using hooks to manage states and conditional rendering.

**The Tech Blog** — <u>Repository</u> | <u>Application</u> — *A CMS-style blog site* where developers can publish blog posts and comment on other developers' posts.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **University of Utah Online Coding Bootcamp** — *Certification*

APR 2020 - OCT 2020

An intensive and highly accelerated six-month course that teaches the programming languages and skills most commonly used by those in the active workforce to those who afterward become certified and employer-competitive full-stack web developers.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Community Nursing Services,** West Valley, UT— Covid Staff Manager/Front office Staff

August 2020 - PRESENT

Oversee the hiring and scheduling of Nurses and Clerks to work at the University of Utah Covid Testing Tents. Also handle Covid screening for patients entering the immunization clinic and enter immunization records into USIIS.

### **California Pizza Kitchen,** Salt Lake City, UT—Server/Host/Busser

Oct 2016 - Mar 2018 & Dec 2019 - Jan 2020

Handled the serving of guests, taking orders, and handling payment. Greeted guests and handled customer feedback. Cleaned tables and surfaces. Kept up with a high paced environment.



### **Contact Me**

8319 Cobble Creek Dr.
West Jordan, UT 84081
(385) 237-6420
zach.whiting@icloud.com
LinkedIn Portfolio Github

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & APPLICATION PROGRAMMING INTERFACES

JavaScript	jQuery
(ES5 & ES6)	Bootstrap
Node	Bulma
Express	SQLite
React	MySQL
MongoDB	Sequelize
Mongoose	Handlebars
HTML 5	AJAX
Advanced CSS	Jest
	Git

#### **OTHER SKILLS**

Object Oriented Programming
Functional Programming
Test Driven Development
Object-Relational Mapping
Model, View, Controller
Representational State Transfer
(RESTful) APIs
Progressive Web Applications
Agile Project Management